恶魔城
第四季 第７集
‎这个把戏很有用
The trick worked.
‎你在那个人身上
The stupid little trinkets
发现的愚蠢小挂件吗
you found on that human body?
‎我认为他们从自己的宫廷偷东西
I think they steal things from their own court,
‎带在身上当护身符或者原始的物件
carrying them as talismans or some primitive shit.
‎我们一直找不到地下宫廷
The underground court we've never been able to find.
‎我一直怀疑 他们是不是‎用圣水混淆了
I always wondered if they were confusing our senses
我们的感官
with holy water.
‎然后有个白痴出现了 ‎
And then some idiot shows up
脖子上带着占卜工具
with a divining set around his neck,
可能认为这会让他刀剑不入
probably thinking it would make him resistant to swords.
‎在那里 ‎‎那里就是他们的地下宫廷
There. That's their underground court.
‎她从那里拿走了这块追踪石
She took the tracking stone right there.
‎我的计划太棒了
My plan was magnificent.
‎这不是你的计划
It wasn't your plan.
‎这是我的计划
It was my plan.
‎你只是同意了这个计划
You just agreed to it.
‎我同意了 所以这成了我的计划
Well, I gave my assent, therefore it became my plan.
你该庆幸我还记得你也在场
Be happy I even remember you're here.
‎你刚刚对我说什么
What did you just say to me?
‎你听到了
You heard me.
‎德古拉伯爵派我来这里
Dracula sent me here.
‎我曾经把塔哥维斯特作为礼物送给他
I was to make Targoviste a gift to him.
‎现在我要让他起死回生 ‎再把这里作为礼物送给他
Now I will return him to earth and present it to him.
‎你只是我的小帮手
You're just my little helper.
‎去死吧 瓦尼
Fuck you to hell, Varney.
‎我再也不会
I am entirely fucking finished
‎为了把事情做好 支持你那些
with propping up your delusional bullshit
妄想的胡说八道了
just to get things done.
‎什么
What?
‎我是个士兵
I am a soldier.
‎我还不知道你他妈到底是什么人
I still do not know what the fuck you are supposed to be.
‎我是伦敦的瓦尼 ‎你这个傲慢的斯拉夫傻逼
I'm Varney of London, you insolent Slavic pissflap.
‎你就是个笑柄
You're a joke!
‎你是个浅薄的罪犯
You're a shallow criminal
‎不知用了什么手段 在一百年前‎混进了
who somehow wormed your way into Dracula's circle
德古拉伯爵的圈子
a hundred years ago.
‎然后他让你大老远跑到这里
And then he sent you all the way out here,
‎来到这座他已经烧毁的城市
to the city he'd already burned.
‎他到底认为你有多大用处
How useful did he really think you are?
事情...
That's...
‎事情不是这样的
That's not what happened.
‎闭嘴
Shut up.
‎拉科 我的孩子 你也是罪犯
Oh, Ratko, my boy, you're a criminal too.
-‎我了解你  -‎你根本不了解我
- I know you. - You don't fucking know me.
‎我了解你
I know you.
‎我闻到了你身上的死亡气息
I smell the death on you.
‎你犯过罪
You've committed crimes.
‎我打过仗
I've practiced war.
‎打仗是军队在战场上的交锋
War is armies meeting each other on the field of combat.
-‎那不是你做的事  -‎没错
- That's not what you do. - Right.
‎我是聪明的士兵
I'm a clever soldier.
‎我是忠诚的士兵
I'm a committed soldier.
‎我不爱出风头
I don't go to pageants.
‎我不耍花招
I don't play games.
‎你是在为自己狡辩吗
Are you justifying yourself?
‎吃屎去吧 ‎我打过仗
Eat shit. I fight wars.
‎你不知道 对吗
You have no idea, do you?
‎打仗就是你杀了对方那么多人
War is when you kill so many of the other side
‎他们再也不能和你战斗
that they can't fight you anymore.
‎趾高气扬地走过草地不是打仗
Prancing around on a meadow isn't war.
‎偷偷溜进帐篷
Stealing into a tent
‎割断每个人的喉咙 这才是打仗
and cutting every throat in sight is war.
‎在井里下毒是打仗
Poisoning wells is war.
‎杀光镇上的孩子 然后消失不见 ‎这才是打仗
Killing every baby in a town and disappearing, that's war.
‎打仗就是为了赢
War is for winning.
‎追踪那个疯子潜入她的密室
And tracking that lunatic down into her secret rooms
‎把他们吓死
and surprising them to death,
这就是我做的事
that's what I do.
‎这就是我做过的事
That's what I did.
‎而你站在那里 装模作样
And you, standing there flapping and posing.
‎你是我最讨厌的人
You're everything I hate.
‎你们吸血鬼以为智慧最重要
You vampires who think it's all about wit.
‎我用不着多说
I use the word loosely,
‎因为你是个绝无仅有的蠢货
because you are a shithead for the ages.
‎装腔作势 咬文嚼字
Being charming, using clever words,
‎不顾一切地想让人们佩服你
desperate for people to admire you
‎因为你很特别
because you're special.
‎你身上有太多残破恶劣的人性
Too much of the damaged, needy human on you.
‎你不是吸血鬼
You're not a vampire.
‎我他妈才是吸血鬼
I'm a fucking vampire.
‎我撒谎 骗人
I lie and I cheat,
‎因为对猪撒谎毫无意义
because lying to pigs is meaningless,
‎我也很饿
and I'm hungry.
‎我抢走别人拥有的一切
I take everything anybody has,
‎一点都不留
every last fucking drop,
‎然后我寻找更多猎物
and then I hunt for more.
‎我不是罪犯
I am not a criminal.
‎我太他妈完美了
I am fucking perfect.
‎哦 亲爱的年轻人
Oh, dear, young man.
-‎完美吗  -‎完美
- Perfect? - Perfect.
‎我被派到世上来
I was given to the Earth
‎我想吃什么就吃什么
to feed off everything on it as I choose.
‎我告诉你 拉科
Well, let me tell you, Ratko,
‎你不知道我是什么人
you do not know what I am.
‎但我能容忍你 因为你擅长杀人
But I tolerate you precisely because you're good at death.
‎死人滋养了我
It nourishes me.
‎随便吧
Whatever.
‎你让我生气
You made me angry.
‎我不喜欢生气
I don't like to be angry.
‎为什么不呢 生气会让你杀人
Whyever not? Anger makes you kill, surely.
‎我敢说你甚至在梦里杀人
I bet you even kill in your dreams.
‎在我的梦里 ‎我很冷静
In my dreams, I am calm.
‎我只能走动 恐惧和饥饿
I am nothing but motion, and fear, and hunger,
‎全世界所有的人
and all the people in the world
‎像畜栏里的动物一样排着队
are lined up like animals in pens
‎等着我去吸他们的血
for me to bite the blood from.
‎人们会忘记我们是什么人
People forget what we are.
‎你到底要去哪里
Where do you think you're going?
‎看来你们已经接手了地面的工作
Well, you seem to have taken over the effort aboveground.
‎我要去处理别的事情了
And I have other things to attend to.
‎对 尤其是有一件事
Yeah. One thing in particular.
‎听着 我们在浪费时间
Look, we're done screwing around.
‎你要给我们看传说中的地下宫廷
You are going to show us your fabled underground court.
‎然后我们要让这里秩序井然
And then we are going to get this place in proper order,
‎保卫人民 清理城市
defend the people and clean out the city.
‎明白了吗
Are we clear?
‎我想是时候带你们去地下宫廷了
I think it's time for you to go to the Underground Court.
‎是啊 我刚刚不是这么说的吗
Yeah, isn't that what I just said?
‎我不知道
Oh, I don't know.
你刚才唠叨想要什么
I stopped listening a second or two
‎后来我就没听你说话了
after you started mewling about what you want.
‎然后我决定 是时候让你们跟着我了
Then I decided it was time for you to follow me.
‎认清你们的处境
Know your place.
‎我们先看看这个地方 好吗
Let's take a look at this place first, hm?
‎真是杰作
Masterly, masterly.
‎多么糟糕的涂鸦
What an awful bloody daub.
‎没人会留意这里
Nobody's going to miss that.
‎我找到位置了
I have the location,
我正在做准备
and I am preparing the way.
‎现在该追求准确和卓越
It is the time for accuracy, excellence,
‎还要相信你们这些人的勇气
and whatever passes for courage in you people.
‎嘘
Boo.
‎你真是好人
That was nice of you.
‎我没发现还有人在看
I didn't realize anyone was watching.
‎我在找你
I was looking for you.
‎想象一下 我有多惊讶 你从天而降
Imagine my surprise when you dropped out of the sky
‎把这些小混蛋吓得魂飞魄散
and frightened a year's growth out of the little bastards.
‎抱歉
Sorry.
‎不 说真的
No, really.
‎你是个好人
It was nice of you.
‎根本没有一个大人
They don't all have an adult
会关注他们
who'll pay any attention at all to them.
‎更不用说像死神一样
Let alone plummet down on them
从天而降出现在他们面前了
like death from above, I suppose.
‎你让他们有了一个永远流传下去的故事
You gave them a story they'll be telling forever.
‎我听到他们在笑
I heard them laughing.
‎这里好久没有孩子们的欢笑了
It's been a while since children laughed here.
‎你找我有事吗
You were looking for me?
‎我想跟你谈谈防御的事
I wanted to talk to you about defenses.
‎我还想问问你的食物供应
And I wanted to ask about your food supplies.
‎我不确定有多少食物
I'm not sure there's much.
‎问题就在这里
Well, that's the thing.
‎我希望我们可以用一些你的肉干
I was hoping we could use some of the dried meat you have
‎把饭菜做得更好一些
to make meals go a little further?
‎都用了吧
Use it all.
‎真的吗 ‎
Seriously?
不管你能找到什么
Whatever you can find.
‎我早上吃新鲜的食物
I tended to forage fresh food in the mornings,
‎但我肯定储藏室里有一些腌制食品
but I'm sure I have some preserved things in the pantries.
‎你不知道你的城堡里有什么吗
You don't actually know what you've got in your castle, do you?
‎不太清楚
Not really.
‎看来你几个月前还能养活
It looks like you were feeding an army in there
一支军队
up until a couple of months ago.
‎是啊...
Well...
‎那不是我的本意
that wasn't me.
‎但我明白你的意思
But I take your point.
‎我有点心事
I've been preoccupied.
‎除了弥补造成的伤害…
Beyond clearing up some of the damage from...
‎我们谈点别的吧
Let's talk about something else.
‎防御
Defenses.
‎我是说 ‎我希望只要关上城堡大门
I mean, I hope just closing your castle doors
‎就能把人挡在外面 但是…
will keep people away, but...
‎天很快就要黑了
We're going to start losing the light soon.
‎我带你去看存放武器的地方...
Let me show you where the weapons are kept...
‎然后再看看外面
and then we'll look at the outside.
‎我们记得黑人拉杜
We remember Radu the Black.
‎我的天啊
Oh, my God.
‎在这里等着
Wait here.
‎我的天啊
Bloody hell.
‎我知道
I know.
‎这太可怕了
This is horrible.
‎对 但我不是那个意思
Yeah, but that's not what I meant.
‎什么
Huh?
‎不可能
Can't be.
‎你发现新玩具了吗
You found a new toy?
‎我不知道
I don't know.
‎不是玩具
Not a toy.
‎到底是什么啊
What on earth is it?
‎据传说 ‎有个疯狂的挪威吸血鬼猎人
Well, the story goes that a mad Norwegian vampire hunter
去了印度
went to India,
‎他说服了拉贾普特拉部族的‎兵器大师
and he convinced the weapons master of the Raja-Putra clans
给他做了这个
to make him this thing.
‎世上仅此一件
There's only one.
‎我在我母亲的书里看过画像
I saw drawings of it in my mother's books.
‎真正的问题是 怎么会在这里
The real question is how it ended up here.
‎看到了吗 十字架标志
See? Sign of the cross.
‎这个吸血鬼猎人死在印度了
Did the vampire hunter die in India?
‎因为印度吸血鬼根本不知道
Because Hindu vampires wouldn't have the faintest idea
‎他为什么挥舞十字架
why he was waving a cross at them.
‎那倒不是
Actually, no.
‎吸血鬼基本上是进化的捕食者
Vampires are basically an evolved predator species,
‎所以他们的视力与我们有很大不同
so their eyesight is pretty different to ours.
‎如果你用巨大的几何形物体
Turns out that if you put a big geometric shape
‎逼近他们的视野
right up close in their field of vision,
‎这会迷惑他们的大脑
it confuses the shit out of their brains
‎让他们惊慌失措
and, you know, makes them panic.
‎你怎么知道这个
How do you even know that?
‎哦 我曾经想成为英勇的怪物猎人
Yeah, I learned all kinds of things
‎我为此学到了很多东西 记得吗
when I was going to be a heroic monster hunter, remember?
‎后来发生了这些破事
And then all the shit happened,
‎我就慢慢地全忘了
and bit by bit I suppose I lost it all.
‎现在我又开始回忆起来
And now I'm starting to pick it all up again.
‎问题是
The question is,
‎如果你把这东西扔在这里
if you're keeping stuff like this down here,
‎那你为什么不在地面上用呢
then why aren't you using it up there?
‎因为你的君主希望如此
Because your betters wish it so.
‎那我该见见他们了
Then it's time I meet them.
‎从这里进去见他们吗
Are they through there?
‎我没说你可以见他们
Oh, I didn't say you could meet them.
‎他们在休息
They're resting.
‎好吧 是时候从沉睡中醒来了
Yeah, well, time to stop sleeping through all this.
‎看着我的眼睛
Look into my eyes.
‎你现在真的想让我的生活
Do you really, really want to make my life
更烦心吗
any more annoying right now, hm?
‎醒醒 你们这群混蛋
Wakey wakey, you shower of assholes.
‎你不能这样对他们说话
You cannot speak to them like that.
‎我明白他们
Well, I see why
‎为什么对任何事都漠不关心了
they're so remarkably unconcerned about everything.
‎求你小声点
Keep your voice down.
‎为什么 他们又不会醒来
Why? They're not going to wake up.
‎这里的其他人不知道王室的沉睡
The others here don't understand about the royal sleep.
噢
Oh.
‎没错
Yeah.
‎扎姆菲尔 ‎这两个人需要安息
Zamfir, these two need to be laid to rest.
‎这样真的不行
This is just wrong.
‎你们有神父吗
Do you have a priest?
‎没有神父
No priests.
‎扎姆菲尔 听我说
Zamfir, listen to me.
‎这都结束了
This is over.
‎永远不会结束
It will never be over.
‎末日永远不会征服我们
The apocalypse will never claim us.
塔哥维斯特的灾难永远不会再发生
The catastrophe of Targoviste will never happen again.
‎我们杀了所有神父
We killed all the priests, you see.
‎真的吗
Really.
‎我们正在夺回对国家的控制权
We are taking back control of our country.
塔哥维斯特不是国家
Targoviste isn't a country.
‎是这个国家跳动的心脏
It's the beating heart of the country.
‎连城市都不是
Not even a city.
‎这是世界上最伟大的城市
It's the greatest city in the world.
‎我们是城市的管理者
We are its stewards.
‎-我们要夺回控制权 ‎-控制权 是的
- We're taking back control. - Control? Yes.
‎让你们的人民挨饿
Letting your people starve
‎从自己的粪便旁边走过
and swim around in their own shit.
‎不帮助组织他们
Not helping them organize.
不帮助他们自卫
Not helping them defend themselves.
‎我还没给他们擦屁股呢
I haven't been wiping their asses either.
‎我是不是应该拿着破布赶过去
Should I nip back up there with some rags?
‎你可以试着帮他们
You could try giving them the aid
过自己的生活
to live their damn lives.
你看
Look!
‎我们带了这么多人到下面
We've taken so many people in down here.
‎是的 你收留的这些人
Yes, you've made an interesting collection
明显将死于忽视
of people who are clearly dying of neglect.
‎我们在地下宫廷没有忽视任何人
We neglect no one in the Underground Court.
‎这些人嘴唇干裂
These people have cracked lips,
后面就有流水
and you have flowing water back there.
‎我们需要水来防御
We need that. For defense.
‎圣水
Holy water.
‎你杀了所有神父 从哪弄来的圣水
Where did you get it if you killed all the priests?
‎我们从没有受损的宗教建筑里找到的
We recovered it from intact religious buildings.
‎你知道有些神父曾经把圣水‎装在木桶
Do you know some of them used to cask and bottle
和瓶子里卖吗
holy water to sell?
‎你可以把圣水给人们饮用
You could have used it to give people something to drink.
‎我们必须保卫宫廷
The court must be defended.
‎要是我们让人们喝光圣水
What if we'd let people drink it all,
‎吸血鬼穿过干涸的地道
and then vampires crossed empty channels
‎进入宫廷杀死所有人 该怎么办
to enter the court and kill everybody?
‎当然 你不能冒险让吸血鬼进来
Sure. You couldn't risk letting vampires in.
‎他们可能已经准备好了
They might have tidied up.
‎这根本不管用
Oh, that doesn't even work.
而且你保护的是两具尸体
And you're defending two dead bodies.
‎他们会醒来的
They will wake.
‎陛下会从王室沉睡中醒来
Their majesties will awaken from their royal sleep
‎拯救我们所有人
and save us all.
‎你疯了
You're insane.
‎我当然是疯了
Of course I'm insane.
‎究竟怎么了
The fuck what now?
‎德古拉进城的那天 我就疯了
I went insane the day Dracula hit the city.
‎我在天空中看到他的脸
I saw his face in the sky.
‎就像恶魔本人摧毁了世界
It was like the devil himself punched the world.
‎看到地狱触碰你的家园
How could you not lose your mind,
‎你怎么能不发疯呢
seeing hell touch your home?
‎从那以后 我每晚仅睡两个小时
I sleep for two hours a night and wake up screaming
‎然后尖叫着醒来
ever since it happened.
‎所以你还没疯到不知道自己疯了
So you're not so crazy that you don't know you're crazy?
‎他们会醒来的
They will wake.
他们是魔法师
They are magicians.
‎他们有王室血统
They are royal blood.
‎他们在隐秘的王国旅行
They journey in the subtle realms
‎以恢复他们的力量
to recover their strength,
‎在此之前 我必须保护他们
and I have to defend them until then.
‎我现在懂了
I get it now.
‎你已经受苦太久了
You have been suffering for so long.
‎你是德古拉伯爵来袭时‎最后一个
Were you the last person of noble birth left alive
活着的贵族吗
when Dracula struck?
‎我没有受苦
I am not suffering.
‎这是一项伟大的事业
This is the great work.
‎这是我光荣的职责
This is my glorious duty.
‎通过拯救他们 我将拯救所有人
I will save everyone by saving them.
‎难怪他们把它打碎了
Well, no wonder they broke it into pieces.
‎是你把他们从宫殿废墟里拖出来的吗
Did you drag them out of the ruins of their palace?
‎那是我的责任 我救了他们
It was my job. I saved them.
‎他们会醒来的
They will wake.
‎他们会拯救我们所有人
They will save us all.
‎一切就会回归正常
And everything will be set right.
‎一切都将恢复原样
Everything will be as it was.
‎他们是魔法师 赛珐
They are magicians, Sypha.
‎是吗
Are they?
‎神父阶层总是怀疑这件事
The priest class always suspected it.
‎他们骚扰王室 你能相信吗 但你看
They harried the royal family. Can you believe it? But look.
‎看看我们从他们的宫殿里‎找到的所有东西
Look at all the things we recovered from their palace.
‎看看他们神秘的宝藏
Behold their mystical treasures.
‎我救了他们 所以他们会救我
I saved them. So they will save me.
‎你在那边浪费时间浪费够了没
Are you done farting around over there?
‎我不知道是谁教你这些话的 不过 浪费够了
I don't know who taught you all these words, but yeah.
‎好 很好
Okay. Good.
‎对于发生在你身上的一切 ‎我真的很抱歉
I am truly sorry for everything that has happened to you.
‎但现在必须停止这一切
But all this has to stop now.
‎什么
W-What?
‎我们需要帮助这些人
We need to get these people help.
‎我们需要给健康的人
We need to arm the healthy ones
‎装备你这里的武器
with the weapons you have down here.
‎我们需要放弃这个地方 组织…
We need to abandon this space, organize and...
‎放弃
Abandon?
‎放弃王室吗
Abandon the royal family?
‎这是个烂摊子
This is a mess.
‎你尽力了 但你的统治者已经死了
You did the best you could, but your rulers are dead
‎人民需要你
and the people need you.
‎不 我救了他们
No. I saved them.